Guide to the Leonard Shaw Papers RG.008
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Leonard Shaw Papers
1978-2003
1978-1998
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Shaw, Leonard
RG.008
8
1 Linear Feet One box
Leonard Shaw served as Head of the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science from 1982 – 1990, then as the Dean of the School of EE and CS until 1994. Throughout his time both teaching and in his leadership roles, Shaw was an active member of the faculty, helping to plan and execute joint programs with institutions abroad in Iran and Italy, as well as courses offered in the Picatinny Arsenal in New Jersey and on the Brooklyn campus.
Box 1
Biographical / Historical
Professor Leonard Shaw joined the faculty at Polytechnic University in 1960, where he taught Electrical Engineering (EE) for 43 years. During that time, Shaw also served as the Head of the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science from 1982- 1990, and then Dean of the School of EE and CS until 1994.
Arrangement
Series are arranged by subject. Items are arranged chronologically.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research without restrictions.
Scope and Contents
The Leonard Shaw Papers includes departmental records, memorandum, and correspondence concerning the Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Department from 1973 through 1999.
This collection documents the merger with NYU in 1973 and some of the effects on the EE/CS Department and students, primarily in regards to confusion surrounding graduation requirements. This collection also contains records from the departmental decision to eventually phase-out the evening course offerings for the BS in EE program in 1989. Also included in the collection are records of the planning, implementation, and assessment of joint EE degree programs offered in cooperation with both Reiss-Romoli in Italy in the early 1990s and the School of Television and Cinema in Tehran, Iran in the late 1970s. Lastly, the collection contains records of the National Science Foundation Graduate Research Traineeship from 1993 through 1999.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; there is no documentation concerning the provenance of these materials.
Memoranda; Universities and colleges -- Mergers -- New York; Merger - NYU-Poly - 1973; Picatinny Arsenal; Electrical engineering; Engineering; Computer science; National Science Foundation (U.S.); Polytechnic University (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.) -- Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science; Polytechnic University (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.); Scuola superiore guglielmo Reiss Romoli
- Series I: Polytechnic University and NYU Merger, 1973-1989; 5823 (Box 1)
  - Department of Electrical Engineering and Electrophysics, 1973-1976; 5831 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Phase-out of Evening BS in EE Program, 1989; 5826 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Joint programs, 1978-1990; 5829 (Box 1)
  - Joint EE Program with School of Television and Cinema, Iran, 1978-1979; 5824 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Joint MS Program with Reiss-Romoli, 1989- 1990, 5827 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Joint MS Program with Reiss-Romoli, 1991- 1992, 5833 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series III: Graduate Programs, 1982-1999; 5830 (Box 1)
  - Graduate Courses at Picatinny Arsenal, NJ, 1982-1995; 5825 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - National Science Foundation Graduate Research Traineeship, 1993-1999; 5828 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - National Science Foundation Graduate Traineeship Report, 1998; 5834 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Acquisition Note, 2003; 5832 (Box 1, Folder 9)